Welcome to the exciting world of digital arts and graphic design.
Take a minute to look around you. What do you see?
Books, computers, mobile devices.
Perhaps the TV is on or you can see advertisements on billboards or in a magazine.
All of these things have been created with the help
of digital artists and graphic designers.
Digital art, simply put,
is any artwork created digitally,
stall on a computer,
a mobile phone, for example.
Anyone who creates art on a computer is a digital artists.
Many digital artist create work for both personal and commercial purposes.
A graphic designer is also a digital artist.
One who, in addition to creating artwork,
also helps create the more explicit messaging
like text that generally goes with the art work.
This is a simple example of a difference between the two.
Keep in mind though, that some digital artists use words in their practice,
and not every graphic designer will use words all of the time.
They are two very interrelated avenues
that really come down to what you wish to call yourself.
Therefore, you may see me using
the words digital artist and graphic designer interchangeably.
The job of a digital artist or graphic designer is to be a problem-solver.
We provide visual solutions that can,
for instance, persuade you to buy something or to not buy something.
We can educate you on
public safety measures can charm you with cute images of baby animals.
We brand companies big and small,
and create visual components so recognizable that when you see them,
you know exactly what the company is without even seeing the brand name.
The role of the graphic designer can be as
exciting as giving your favorite brand's image.
Think about large companies who we instantly
recognize without even having to see their names,
think of the swoosh symbol and athletic wear or another very famous swooping arrow
delivering packages or a very famous piece of fruit with a bite taken out of it.
All of these symbols were made by graphic designers