As a graphic designer,
my biggest job is to solve problems for my clients.
Usually, this means creating what we call a brand identity.
Simply put, this is the logo for the client and then any and
all materials and items that may have their logo applied to them.
One very special client was a group of young people in
Nicaragua who had started a furniture business using recycled wooden pallets.
It was very important to them that the logo captured not just their brand name,
but represented the fact that the raw materials that
they were using in their company were in fact recycled.
Because of this environmental angle,
they really wanted their brand to use the color green.
Part of my design process is to look for inspiration and research my clients.
As they were using palettes to create furniture,
my immediate go-to for inspiration was, of course, pallets.
On this slide, you can see my initial drafts and thought processes for development.
You will find your own style and process as you begin to learn
more and you will find out what works best for you.
For me, I like to throw all of my ideas onto the art board and see what sticks.
I then go back and further refine ideas before I present to the client.
Sometimes the client says,
"You know what, I actually like something from the first round better."
They were really happy with the end result.
They felt like this logo made them look professional,
but not too corporate,
and that it showed the world what they were all about.
In here, is an example of the logo applied to both print items like
this t-shirt and a digital example as well with a group social media homepage