Have you ever wondered how billboards are designed?
Or the advertisements you see on the sides of buildings or buses?
Conversely, have you ever paid attention to the design of a postage stamp?
Or seeing small graphics perhaps on social media and wondered how they were created.
Well, they were created one of two ways, vector or raster.
In a nutshell, raster designs are
pixel-based and their quality is dependent on their size.
Have you ever tried to enlarge a photo and suddenly got distorted or blurry?
This is because it's based on something called pixels.
The second avenue is vector-based graphics,
and this is where we will focus on.
Before we dive into that though,
let's take a moment to learn what vectors are.
In simple terms, a vector is something like an object with both magnitude and direction.
Look at that little boat.
The magnitude of the boat would be its length,
and the direction would be the arrow moving across the screen to the right.
Now, the river could turn a bend or the boat could change its direction,
so there is the possibility for
many different vectors using the boat in the river, for example.
In the design world,
the vectors we will be working with will scale
up or down so their direction will be outwards or inwards,
and their magnitude will change with the scale of the object.
All of this is a fancy way of saying that no matter what you create,
whether it's small like a postage stamp or big like a billboard advertisement,
at any size it will look exactly the same.
You can scale up or down infinitely without compromising the integrity of the visual.
It is a really cool feature in the design world.
The software does all of the math for us.
So if you were worried because you thought you stumbled
into a math class by mistake, have no fear.
We just needed a basic understanding of how it all works.
What does that mean for you as a designer?
It means that by using a computer or tablet and vector-based software,
you have the capability to design anything for any project of any size.