Now we have a general idea of the space and type of artwork we will be creating.
Let's talk a little about the basics of design.
These are what we call the elements of design.
Here's some of the elements we will talk about throughout our learning journey.
A line. A line is actually an elongated point.
It is the most basic of all of the elements. A shape.
A shape is the general outline of something,
or a closed form or closed path.
Color. Now color is perhaps the element we are most familiar with.
In the digital world,
we will learn about additive colors, RGB.
Now, RGB stands for red, green, and blue,
and all of the colors that you see on the screen are made up of those three colors.
Space. Now space is otherwise referred to as figure ground or negative space.
This refers to the space around the objects and it is as
much an element as the objects themselves.
Typography. Now, most people don't even
think about the letters they see on the screen or in print.
They just read the information provided.
But typography itself is an art form.
Lastly, we have texture.
In the digital world, we can't create texture that we can
physically feel or tactile texture.
Instead, we create visual texture or artworks that look like it has texture.
In this first example,
we have something similar to a quick pencil sketch.
The second example is radial and it appears like the screen has a rounded texture to it.
The third example is layered shapes that give some depth by mimicking shadow.
It's good to know that we can use texture to help give dimension.
The elements are the backbone of design.
They are the building blocks for all of your digital creations.
Both those who create artwork as a hobby and the professionals who create
brands for international companies all rely on these elements