Line, shape, color, space,
type, and texture are the basic building blocks of design.
Now, let's look at how to turn these individual objects into an effective visual design.
We do this by using what are called the principles of design.
They are balance and scale.
Balance is visual stability,
meaning that there is an even distribution of the elements in the composition,
like you see in this example.
Scale is the size of the elements.
These two work hand in hand together.
Even though the odd number of circles we see are all different scales,
because of their visual placement,
the composition remains balanced.
Contrast and pattern.
Opposing elements that play off of each other,
like these white circles against that dark blue background can often turn into patterns.
That is why these two go hand in hand most of the time.
Movement. When you think of movement,
think of the rhythm of a song.
A composition should have elements that move the eye around the page.
Emphasis. Now, emphasis is about visual hierarchy or order of visual importance.
On the screen, you can see that this center circle
has been made larger than all of the other elements.
This is a visual clue that it may be more important than the other elements.
Unity. Now a good way to describe unity is when all of
the individual elements worked so well together that they make up a whole composition.
These are a little bit more advance,
so we won't worry too much about them now.
However, you will begin to see
these words and it is important to know what we are referencing.
Before long, you will have a solid knowledge of
both the elements and the principles of design.