Line. It seems so simple.
We study them, we draw them,
and we hardly ever think about them. They are just there.
But there's a lot more to it.
Let's take a closer look at the most basic of elements line.
Let's get right to the point. That's right.
The point, take out a pen or a pencil and make a dot on a piece of paper.
That dot in the digital realm is actually a line.
It is in fact,
the smallest unit of line and it only gets bigger from there.
Now, I want you to repeat that simple exercise,
but drag the pen or pencil across the paper and you have a line,
which is actually just an elongated point.
When we create this elongated point or line on the computer,
we are creating something that has magnitude and direction.
When something has those two things,
what do we know to be true?
Yes, that is correct.
The digital line is a vector graphic.
This simplest of all elements.
Lines can have many different qualities.
They can be straight or wavy,
and they can be downright curly.
They can be solid or broken.
They can snake across the entire screen,
or they can appear just at the edges.
They can be thick or very narrow.
A general rule of thumb with line is this.
They're usually longer than they are wide.
Let's take a closer look at some of the categories of line.
We have solid, which is one continuous line.
Implied line. This can be dotted or dashed.
Although technically each dot or dash is a line,
the human eye will see it as one continuous line.
That is because of something called gestalt.
Now, gestalt simply means that we see the entire dashed line as one unit,
instead of seeing each dash as an individual unit. Line of vision.
This is the movement as your eye looks at the composition,
it is also called the line of movement or directional line.
Lines can be used for many functions.
They can make shapes and forms,
they can create borders and edges,
and they can help organize and assist someone in how they look at a design.
In fact, line has its own style.
If the main element is line then the style is called linear