Even though this is supposed to be a learning journey about digital arts,
you'll be asked to draw by hand as well.
Sometimes it is helpful as designers to first
create a hand drawing as part of the design process.
Even if you feel like you don't know how to draw, it's okay.
You won't be graded on your sketches.
Take out a piece of paper or open your sketchbook if you have
plain unlined paper and may work best for you and grab something to draw with.
For this demo, I want you to take out a piece of paper or open your sketch book.
If you have plain unlined paper,
it will probably work best for you.
Grab something to draw with.
I prefer a marker.
Let's spend a couple of minutes trying to recreate the artwork that you see.
Try to draw one continuous line across the page without lifting or stopping.
Notice how the quality of the line changes.
When you go to draw the next line,
perhaps you start from the opposite side of the paper.
Adapt your next line to the quality of
the first line and repeat until you have created something that you are happy with.
There's no need to fill the entire sheet unless you want to.