Now, let's learn how to create digitally.
Throughout this course, we will be working with free open-source software called Canva.
There are many different options for designing and creating artwork on the computer.
Here are some steps we will take to complete this activity.
Let's start this exercise by opening Canva on our computers and setting up our accounts.
I've just opened Canva,
and this is what you see when you'll open it.
Up here in the upper right-hand corner is a button that says create, design.
If we hover over that, we get this drop-down menu.
We're going to go down to Custom Size.
There's lots of built-in sizes that are already there;
templates and whatnot,
but if we go down here to the bottom and click "Custom size",
we get this drop-down menu.
Let's go ahead and make 1,000 pixels by 1,000 pixels.
That gives us a nice square to work with and so go ahead,
you can hit those numbers and click "Create new design".
What do we have here?
We have a blank artboard and to give you a little tour of Canva.
This is your artboard,
this is the workable space,
and over here on the left,
we've got some built-in features.
On the far left, we've got our main components of the software.
Let's go ahead and click on "Elements".
Right here we have some built-in elements,
and why don't we go ahead and click on lines and shapes?
It's right here, it's the second one down.
Learning about lines, we can see that there's some built-in line functions here in Canva.
We can click on any of these.
Here is a solid line and it pops up right in
the center and so there are a few things about this that we can look at.
If we look at these little arrows right here and hover over it,
you can see that it turns purple,
and if we hold down our mouse,
we can see that we can rotate this line in any direction.
There's the angle that pops up and there's also these two circles on the side that
we can drag in any direction to create the line length,
whether we want it longer or shorter.
If we go up here to this toolbar,
this first one is where we can change the color of our line.
We can give it any color we like;
purple, red, it doesn't matter.
Let's stick with this purple that we have right here and then this next one, line style.
This is where we can change it from a solid line to a dotted line,
change the size of the dots.
Right here is how we make the line thicker.
The higher the number, the heavier the weight.
If we go back to our solid line,
we can see that this is a nice thick line.
Then one last little thing here,
if we toggle this on and off,
that gives us a nice rounded edge to our lines
instead of the straight looking almost like a rectangle.
That's a nice way to soften those.
We can go ahead and decrease the weight of that.
A couple of other things.
If you have this clicked,
we can add ends to our lines as well.
If we want it to be an arrow or a circle at the end,
this is a way that we can change our lines.
We can also change it from a straight to an elbow line.
If we go ahead and click out of that,
we have a line here.
That's one way to create a line.
The second way that we can create a line in Canva is by using the draw tools here.
On the left-hand side,
if we click on Draw,
we get some markers and some different size things that pop up.
Go ahead and click on this marker and we can just free-hand a line.
Obviously, this isn't as clean as the straight lines that Canva gives us,
and it gives us a much more organic or natural field to the line.
Again, for my artists out there who like to freehand draw things,
this might be a tool that's good for you.