Congratulations, you have just completed your first lesson.
We have learned so much already.
To recap, we now know that the practices of digital art and graphic design create most,
if not all of the visuals we see around us in our everyday life.
We have learned that most of
this digital art work is created using vector-based graphics,
and that these can be produced at any size with the exact same results.
We also learned about the elements and principles,
the basic building blocks of design,
and we learned how to implement the first to the elements line using Canva,
a free open-source software.
Wow, we covered so much already.
You are well on your way to becoming digital artists and graphic designers.